

# **Fiacre**

Nsanzabandi

DATE OF BIRTH:

11/07/1988

## **CONTACT**

Nationality: Burundian

Gender: Male

60 Rue de la gare, Residence Capellen 8325 Capellen, Luxembourg





https://fiacre-nsanzabandi.com

# **ABOUT ME**

I am a software engineer experienced in Java EE programming. After 6 years of professional life in application development, I find it easy to integrate new projects and quickly acquire new knowledge on new subjects. I consider myself a dynamic, versatile and autodidact person and that allows me to be a very good team player. I like sharing the developer experience and it motivates me to move towards the professions of "tech leader", "team leader" or "scrum master".

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### 01/05/2019 - CURRENT

# **Developer for different customers and internal projects**

Sopra Steria

#### Clients

- UCM (Union des classes moyennes)
- BCP Luxembourg
- SIB (Steria interconection box)
- Sopra Steria digilab

## **Tasks**

- Conception & development of Java EE applications
- Participation in different POCs (Proof of concepts) aimed at improving the existing

## **Technical environment:**

- WEB programming: Java EE, Spring batch, Spring boot, Angular, HTML5, CSS3
- Mobile programming: Android
- IT Ops & cloud: Docker, kubernetes, Google cloud platform, Ansible
- Collaboration & integration: Git, Jira, Jenkins 2, Maven, SVN
- Database: Oracle, Mysql

Methodology: Agile, scrum

Leudelange, Luxembourg

## 01/01/2018 - 30/04/2019

## Developer for the customer " Oney Bank "

Sopra Steria

# **Tasks**

- Conception & development of Java EE applications for the customer
- Technical leader in clean coding

## **Technical environment**

- **WEB programming:** Java EE, Spring boot, Spring batch, HTML5, CSS3, Angular JS
- Collaboration and integration: Git, Jira, Jenkins 2, Maven
- Database: Oracle, Mysgl

Methodology: Agile

**Customer's domain:** Banking

La Madeleine, France

01/02/2016 - 31/12/2017

# Developer for the customer « GIE AGORA » (IT center of the mutual health insurance for farmers in France)

Sopra Steria

## **Tasks**

- Conception & development of Java EE applications for the customer
- Provide corrective maintenance
- Evolutions' costing
- WEB technical leader for new developers
- Analyst and team leader

## **Technical environment**

- WEB Programming: Java EE, Struts, Spring batch, HTML5, CSS3, C etc.
- o Database management tools: COBOL, DB2, CICS
- Collaboration and integration: Jira, CVS
- Applications' performances: JMeter & JProfiler.

# Methodology: Agile

Customer's domain: Insurance

La Madeleine, France

#### 03/03/2014 - 31/01/2016

# Developer for the client « AG2R LA MONDIALE »

Sopra Steria

## Tasks

- o Conception & development of Java EE applications for the customer
- Provide corrective maintenance
- Evolutions' costing
- WEB technical leader for new developers

### Technical environment

- WEBprogramming: Java EE, GWT, JSF, Spring, HTML5, CSS3
- Database management tools: COBOL, DB2, CICS
- o Collaboration & integration: Jira, ARS, ITSM, HPQC, clearcase, CVS

## Functional environment: Insurance

La Madeleine, France

# **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**

01/09/2011 - 01/08/2014 - Rouen, France

# Master's degree in software engineering

Université de Rouen

Professional studies on:

- software development methodologies
- various programming languages (WEB programming, Java, Java EE, C++, C#, etc.)

01/09/2008 - 01/07/2011 - Oran, Algeria

## Bachelor's degree in mathematics & computer science

Université d'Oran

Programming:

∘ Java, C++, Qt

• Functional programming: prolog, CAML. Mathematics: analyzes and algebra

Student scholarship of the Burundian government and UNESCO.

#### 01/09/2007 - 01/06/2008

## Gap year

Student at the University of Tanganyika Lake; Traveling across East Africa.

01/09/2006 - 01/07/2007 - Bujumbura, Burundi

Secondary studies achievement in mathematics and physics
Lycée du Lac Tanganyika

## JOB-RELATED SKILLS

## Job-related skills

- **Programming languages**: Java, Kotlin, typescript, C++, C, C#, SQL, etc.
- **WEB programming**: Java EE (JSP/Servlet, etc.), Spring (Spring boot, Spring MVC, etc.), Angular, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, etc.
- IT Ops & cloud: Docker, kubernetes, Ansible, Google cloud platform
- JavaEE tools/frameworks: Playframework, GWT, Zkoss, JUnit, AspectJ, SoapUI, postman etc.
- Profiling and performances: JMeter et JProfiler
- Mobile development: développeur android junior
- Collaboration et integration: Git, CVS, Maven, Nexus, Sonar, Jenkins, Jira
- Project management: Agile methods (Scrum, XP)
- Development tools (IDE): Eclipse, Intellij
- Database tools: MySQL, Postgresql, Oracle, non-relational databases notions (eXist)
- Servers: Tomcat, TomEE, glassfish, JBoss, Weblogic
- o OS: Linux & Windows

I am a full stack developer: 60% of my time doing java EE and 40% working on other technologies.

## LANGUAGE SKILLS

MOTHER TONGUE(S): French | Kirundi | Swahili

# **English**

Listening <b>C2</b>	Reading <b>C2</b>	Spoken production <b>C2</b>	Spoken interaction <b>C2</b>	Writing <b>C1</b>
German				
Listening <b>B1</b>	Reading <b>B1</b>	Spoken production <b>B2</b>	Spoken interaction <b>B2</b>	Writing <b>B1</b>

## **DRIVING LICENCE**

Driving Licence: AM / Driving Licence: B1 / Driving Licence: B